PERSONAL INFO Brent Palmer

brentpalmer.design | brntpalmer@gmail.com Austin, TX | (512) 939-2848

BACKGROUND

Design leader, manager, and strategist with 10+ year history delivering successful B2B SaaS applications. Consistently surpasses project goals by aligning diverse teams around business outcomes. Actively leverages customer and market data in order to develop high-value features and business opportunities.

EXPERIENCE

Mixpanel | Product Design Manager

Remote | Jun 2022 - Present

Launched the first-ever user research function at Mixpanel, procuring two headcount for researchers. Scaled the product design team from four to nine individual contributors in six months. Overhauled our leveling across the entire Design organization, which saw a 12% increase in employee satisfaction. Gender-balanced staffing and pay to successful outcomes: 30% QoQ ARR growth and 8% increase in NPS score.

Fast | Director of Product Design, Business Group

Remote | Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

Managed four direct reports, and ensured my team shipped valuable, usable, accessible, and quality product releases. Work closely with cross-functional leaders to roadmap plan, define OKRs, and bring two products to market.

Brent Palmer Design LLC | Principal

Remote | Jan 2021 - Present

Product consultant to early-stage SaaS founders, taking five products from idea to Series A funding rounds in just nine months.

Point Health | Principal Product Designer

Austin, TX | Sep 2020 - Jan 2021

Launched the Point Health mobile app for iOS and Android and saw 2,000+ MAUs in Q1 2021. Built the first version of Point Health's Confetti design system across mobile, and web. Hired and coached one Brand Designer and one Senior Product Designer.

Proof (YC W18) | Head of Design

Austin, TX | Jun 2019 - Sep 2020

Led all design workstreams for core offering Proof Experiences and saw MRR increase 300% in 1H of 2020. Spearheaded the design and go-to-market strategy for the launch of Proof Experiences and saw 14% WoW growth in free trial accounts created. Redesigned Proof marketing site, which resulted in a decrease in bounce rate from 40.3% to 24.9% in 3 months.

Carwow | Design Manager

London, UK | Jul 2018 - Apr 2019

Coached a team of four designers across Consumer product teams.

Consolidated user research tools and saved £12k annually. Raised employee engagement score 28% by rolling out 6x6 career development framework.

Formed the Consumer Insights Team (CIT), comprised of Data Analyst Lead, User Research Manager, and Head of Customer Support.

Zendesk | Product Design Manager

Montpellier, FR | May 2016 - Jul 2018

Designed the first version of Zendesk Explore—a \$50M business with 9,500+ customers. Created personas from 70+ customer interviews in 6 months during Zendesk Explore's Alpha and Beta phases. Oversaw product design efforts for Query Builder that drove a 10% attachment rate for trial customers. Defined the direction, process, and principles for data visualization across Zendesk. Hired and managed a Senior Product Designer.

TrendKite | Director of User Experience

Austin, TX | Dec 2014 - Apr 2016

Ran the design practice at TrendKite (Acquired by Cision NYSE:CISN for \$225 million). Designed the first version of core analytics product that saw daily active users grow 200% in six months and \$25M in ARR. Hired and coached a Senior Brand Designer. Built tooling and processes to gather user insights for roadmap planning.

Expero | Lead Visual Designer

Austin, TX | Oct 2013 - Dec 2014

Supported product management teams regarding UX strategy, requirements gathering, and release planning. Applied appropriate user testing methodologies such as observation, card sorting, interviews, and surveys. Responsible for visual design definition, direction, and execution of a given project. Clients included TaskTop, SiliconLabs, and Shell Oil.

PayPal | Lead UX Designer

Austin, TX | Nov 2011 - May 2013

Piloted PayPal point-of-sale program with 12 international retailers bringing in \$12M in revenue. Managed a team of two that developed the first form factor documents specific to PIN pads. Advised point-of-sale strategy, UI standards, and touchscreen methodologies to PayPal leadership.

Additional experience